<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Integration | Janusz Swiatczak's Notes]]></title>
  <link href="http://swiatczak.github.io/blog/categories/integration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://swiatczak.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-07T01:19:38+09:30</updated>
  <id>http://swiatczak.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Janusz Swiatczak]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PeopleSoft HCM/CS Integration After Database Split]]></title>
    <link href="http://swiatczak.github.io/blog/2014/07/07/peoplesoft-hcm-slash-cs-integration-after-database-split/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-07T00:59:22+09:30</updated>
    <id>http://swiatczak.github.io/blog/2014/07/07/peoplesoft-hcm-slash-cs-integration-after-database-split</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago I have been involved in the PeopleSoft HR/Campus Solutions DB split project.</p>

<p>A few interesting topics/discoveries:</p>

<ol>
<li>Delivered subscription peoplecode</li>
<li>Integration Integrity utility (IIU)</li>
<li>Integrity Network</li>
</ol>


<hr/>


<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li><p>Subscription peoplecode (App Package) for handling delivered Sync messages performs some interesting steps. When records contains
required fields and no value is provided for one of such fields in the message (rowset) &ndash; the row containing that record is deleted.</p>

<p>  This has interesting side-effects. When you include a custom field on the delivered records. Mark it as required, and use delivered
  message (and logic) to perform synchronisation you may notice that no values get passed/updated if they are part of the customised
  record.</p>

<p>  This is due to the subscription processing logic, which deletes rows containing records with empty required fields.
  It may be justifiable, however, the logic should indicate the reason (as a warning in the log?) for such removal of data.</p>

<p>  We first noticed this problem, as some data was not synchronised properly even though it was included in the message. We then discovered
  that the data was marked as deleted (in the buffer). Which, interestingly, made us believe there was a bug in the delivered code. Finally,
  we have realised that we had two custom fields (which unfortunately did not follow our naming convention).</p>

<p>  Once, we have cleared the required flag on those fields the data started flowing as expected, and the records were synchronised correctly.</p></li>
<li><p>Integration Integrity Utility (IIU) &ndash; very handy, quite simple user interface, all in all &ndash; recommended for anyone ho has to report on data
discrepancies between split environments</p></li>
<li><p>Integrity Network &ndash; proves to be quite handy when it comes to monitoring of the integration nodes or viewing the messages both for local and remote
nodes. You can check the status of the queues on the remote PeopleSoft databases, view diagnostic information, ping and more.</p>

<p> There do seem to be quite a number of some interesting tools for Integration Admins in PeopleTools version 8.53, and I hope I will be able to
 talk about them a bit more in the future. For now, I am busy moving the pages from my previous blog.</p></li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
